Guide to the Mary Ellen Bute Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Mary Ellen Bute Papers
1907-1985
GEN MSS 603
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
14.85
(36 boxes, including 1 Oversize box)
Scripts, correspondence and photographs documenting the film productions of Mary Ellen Bute and Ted Nemeth. The films represented in this collection include "Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake," "Skin of Our Teeth," and "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking."
Bute, Mary Ellen
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Terry Halladay (1991) and transfer from the Yale Film Study Center (1999, 2007, 2008).
Custodial History
Portions of the collection were donated to the Film Study Center by Ted Nemeth in 1985.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 35: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Related film has been retained by the Yale Film Study Center.
Mary Ellen Bute, 1906-1983
Mary Ellen Bute was a film animator, director and producer. She was a pioneer in adopting electronic techniques for film animation. Early in her career she made animated films in the "visual music" style that synchronized abstract images and music. Her later films were live action and included adaptations of works by James Joyce and Thornton Wilder.
Bute was born in Houston, Texas in 1906. She studied painting at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts in Philadephia and lighting design at Yale University. Her early influences included Leon Theremin and Gerald Warburg and she collaborated with Theremin to produce a paper titled "Light as an art material and its possible synchronization with sound" (1932). Most of Bute's films were produced by Ted Nemeth Studios or Expanding Cinema Studios and her collaborators included Norman McLaren and Melville Webber. Later in life Bute was a founding member of the Women's Independent Film Exchange.
Bute's films include: "Synchromy" (1932 or 1933), "Rhythm in Light" (1934), "Synchromy No. 2" (1935), "Dada" (1936), "Parabola" (1937), "Escape" (1937), "Spook Sport" (1939), "Tarantella" (1940), "Polka Graph" (1947), "Color Rhapsody" (1948), "Imagination" (1948), "New Sensations in Sound" (1949), "Pastorale" (1950), "Abstronic" (1952), "Mood Contrasts" (1953), "The Boy Who Saw Through" (1956, producer), "Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake" (1965-1967), and "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking" (1977-1980, unfinished). Bute's projects also include two adaptations of plays: "Lazarus Laughed" by Eugene O'Neill and "Skin of Our Teeth" by Thornton Wilder (both unfinished).
In 1940 Bute married camera operator and painter Theodore (Ted) Nemeth and they collaborated on many of her projects. Ted Nemeth Studios focused on commercial films and Nemeth also handled the distribution of Bute's films. Bute and Nemeth had two sons: Theodore Jr. and James.
Scope and Contents
The papers document the filmmaking career of Mary Ellen Bute and include papers from Expanding Cinema Studios and Ted Nemeth Studios. The collection contains scripts, notes, correspondence, photographs of film productions and of Mary Ellen Bute, and printed material related to the production of many of Bute's films including "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking," "Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake," and "Skin of Our Teeth." Printed material includes newspaper clippings of reviews and background information, files of images which presumably served as inspiration for images in Bute's films, and other ephemera such as brochures and programs.
The papers span the entirety of Bute's career, though the bulk of them document her later film productions. Since she was unable to complete or release some of these (e.g. "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking") the papers are a unique resource on Bute's work to realize her vision of the films. The papers also provide personal and professional context to Bute's career through her correspondence and personal papers.
The papers also document Bute's research, writing and lectures on the topics of film making and animation and her work to support female film makers through forums such as the Women's Independent Film Exchange.
Material from Bute's early abstract films is mostly related to their distribution and promotion. Papers from later live action films include correspondence, scripts and research material in addition to material related to funding, distribution and promotion. Papers from "Skin of Our Teeth" include correspondence with and notes from Thornton Wilder about the adaptation of his play.
In addition to papers related to Bute's film productions, the collection includes papers from Ted Nemeth Studios. These papers document Nemeth's commercial productions for corporations such as Schlitz, his film "Mobilcolor" (about Charles Dockum, the creator of Mobilcolor projectors) and his work to distribute Bute's films.
The collection also contains personal papers that include family correspondence, photographs and financial and medical records.
Arrangement
Organized into five series and one addition: I. Film Production Material, 1935-1982. II. Business Papers, 1941-1983. III. Personal Papers, 1907-1984. IV. Ted Nemeth Studios Papers, 1939-1985. V. Printed Material, 1936-1985. June 2008 Addition, 1908-1983. The papers are largely organized according to their function, with correspondence, scripts and other documentation filed in different series or under the title of the production as appropriate.
Animation (Cinematography); Animators; Cinematographers; Independent filmmakers; Motion picture producers and directors; Motion pictures; Women motion picture producers and directors; Adaptations (derivative objects); Photographs; Screenplays; Sound recordings; Animators; Cinematographers; Directors; Filmmakers; Bute, Mary Ellen; Dockum, Charles; Joyce, James, 1882-1941; Nemeth, Ted, 1911-1986; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975
- Film Production Material, 1935-1982; Series I; 7.71; (19 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by title of work. Material from Bute's early abstract films is filed together at the beginning of the list under the heading Abstract animated films.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains background and research material, notes, synopses and scripts, correspondence (incoming and outgoing), financial papers, photographs, clippings and ephemera related to the production of Bute's films. The material documents the research, planning, funding, production and promotion of the films.
  The most substantive material documents Bute's films "Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake," "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking" (an unfinished work on Walt Whitman's early years), and "Skin of Our Teeth" (an unfinished adaptation of Thornton Wilder's play).
  Unless otherwise noted, all drafts of scripts are typescripts, some corrected.
  Most correspondence in this series documents Bute's efforts to raise funds and promote specific production projects. She attempted to gain the support of prominent figures such as Clare Boothe Luce and Carl Sagan.
  Clippings and ephemera in this series relate directly to film productions (e.g. reviews and programs) or to themes associated with a particular film (e.g. biographical information about Walt Whitman).
  - Abstract animated films
    - Research material, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Synopses, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Contracts and licenses, 1952-1953, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Preservation Proposal, fragment, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Graphics cards, cardboard, undated
    - Publicity and promotional material, 1953-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 10-15)
    - Clippings, 1935-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 16-21)
  - "The Boy Who Saw Through"
    - Script, undated (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
      Includes a television adaptation entitled "Ernie and the Stranger" by Vivian Dorsett and Elizbeth Miele
    - Correspondence, 1959-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Promotional material, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Clippings, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
  - "Ernie and the Stranger"
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: The Boy Who Saw Through
  - "Lazarus Laughed"
    - Script, several drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 31-37)
  - "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking"
    - Notes and background material, 1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 38-41)
    - Synopsis, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Script, several drafts, 1976-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 43-58)
    - Permits and contracts, 1976-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 59-62)
    - Production schedules and reports, 1971-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 63-68)
    - Production photographs, 1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 69-73)
    - Financial records, 1973-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 74-83)
    - Financial records, 1973-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 84-88)
    - Correspondence
      - 'A' general, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - American Film Institute, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - 'B' - 'E' general, 1975-1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - 'F' - 'L' general, 1975-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 92)
      - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 93)
      - 'M' general, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Moses, Robert, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - 'N' general, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Nemeth, Ted Jr., undated (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - New York Foundation of the Arts, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - 'P' - 'R' general, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 99)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - 'S' general, 1976-1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Sagan, Carl, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - Updike, John, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 103)
      - 'V' - 'W' general, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 104)
      - Correspondence identified by first name only, 1977-1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 105)
      - Unidentified correspondent, 1977 April 22 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Printed material
      - Ephemera related to Walt Whitman, 1976-1980, undated (Box 6, Folder 107-112)
      - Clippings, 1975-1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 113-117)
      - Serials, 1971, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 118-119)
        Specimen Days (1971 edition), West Hills Review (Fall 1980), and Walt Whitman Review (September 1980)
      - Printed sheet music, 1956, undated (Box 6, Folder 120)
      - Prop, 22-caliber CO2-propelled pistol, undated (Box 7)
  - "Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake"
    - Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 121-122)
    - Script, several drafts, 1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 123-126)
    - Script, several drafts, 1965, undated (Box 9, Folder 127-131)
      Includes photocopies of fragmentary damaged originals that were discarded due to mold
    - Correspondence
      - 'A' general, 1965-1981 (Box 9, Folder 132)
      - Arthur Cantor, Inc., 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 133)
      - Astor Cinema, 1960-1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - 'B' - 'C' general, 1964-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - Contemporary Films, Ltd., 1969-1981 (Box 9, Folder 136)
      - 'D' general, 1965-1982 (Box 9, Folder 137)
      - De Luxe Laboratories, 1967-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 138)
      - 'E' -'F' general, 1960-1982 (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Fitelson and Mayers, 1966-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 140)
      - Grove Press, 1968-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 141)
      - 'H' - 'J' general, 1963-1982 (Box 10, Folder 142)
      - James Joyce Society, 1965-1983, undated (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - 'K' - 'M' general, 1965-1983 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      - Museum of Modern Art, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 145)
      - 'N' - 'R' general, 1964-1983, undated (Box 10, Folder 146)
      - 'S' general, 1981-1983, undated (Box 10, Folder 147)
      - Society of Authors, 1959-1969 (Box 10, Folder 148)
      - 'T' general, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 149)
      - University of Kansas, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 150)
      - University of Minnesota, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 151)
      - Viking Press, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 152)
      - 'W' general, 1965-1983 (Box 10, Folder 153)
      - List of names from James Joyce Quarterly mailing list, undated (Box 10, Folder 154)
      - First name only, 1968-1982 (Box 10, Folder 155)
      - Unidentified correspondents, undated (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Photographs, 1963, undated (Box 10, Folder 157-158)
    - Photographs, 1963, undated (Box 11, Folder 159-161)
    - Permits and contracts, 1965-66 (Box 11, Folder 162-164)
    - Production notes, 1961-1982, undated (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Financial papers, 1968-1982, undated (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - Discussion guide, circa 1965 (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - Promotional material, 1965-1966, undated (Box 11, Folder 168-174)
      Includes photocopies of damaged originals that were discarded due to mold
    - Printed material
      - Ephemera, 1978-1982, undated (Box 12, Folder 175-178)
      - Clippings, 1965-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 179-189)
  - "The Skin of Our Teeth"
    - Notes, 1975-1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 190-192)
      Includes handwritten suggestions from Thornton Wilder
    - Scene sketches, undated (Box 13, Folder 193)
    - Outline, undated (Box 13, Folder 194-195)
    - Script, several drafts, 1966-1969, undated (Box 13, Folder 196-203)
    - Script, several drafts, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 204-211)
    - Script, several drafts, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 212-218)
    - Script, several drafts, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 219-227)
    - Script, several drafts, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 228-234)
    - Script, several drafts, undated (Box 18, Folder 235-239)
    - Correspondence
      - 'C' general, 1970-1974 (Box 18, Folder 240)
      - Fitelson and Mayers, 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 241-242)
      - 'H' - 'W' general, 1967-1976 (Box 18, Folder 243)
      - Wilder, Isabel and Thornton, 1960-1981, undated (Box 18a, Folder 244a-o)
      - First name only, 1967-1974 (Box 18, Folder 245)
      - Unidentified correspondents, 1967-1974 (Box 18, Folder 246)
    - Photographs, 1972, undated (Box 19, Folder 247-249)
    - Contracts, 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 250-252)
    - Production notes, 1969-1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 253-256)
    - Promotional material, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 257-258)
    - Printed material
      - Ephemera, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 259)
      - Clippings, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 260-264)
        Includes clippings related to a memorial service for Thornton Wilder
  - Unidentified script, draft, undated (Box 19, Folder 265)
    Formerly in a folder labeled "School -- Bute"
- Business Papers, 1941-1983; Series II; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Series II consists of three subseries: Correspondence, Writings and lectures, and Other Papers.
  Series II consists of papers created during the course of Mary Ellen Bute's career which do not pertain to a specific film production. The papers include general correspondence (incoming and outgoing), Bute's writings, lectures and appearances and writings of others. Writings of Others include scripts sent to Bute by third parties and poems and scripts by James Nemeth and Theodore Nemeth, Jr.
  Material related to specific film productions is filed in Series I.
  - Correspondence
    - 'A' general, 1951-1983 (Box 20, Folder 266)
    - Arlan Pictures Inc., 1950-1953 (Box 20, Folder 267)
      Includes correspondence from Leopold Stokowski
    - 'B' general, 1972-1982 (Box 20, Folder 268)
    - Basquin, Kit, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 269)
    - 'C' - 'N' general, 1952-1983 (Box 20, Folder 270)
    - Nemeth, Theodore, III, 1979, undated (Box 20, Folder 271)
    - 'P' - 'S' general, 1966-1982, undated (Box 20, Folder 272)
    - Starr, Cecile, 1975-1984, undated (Box 20, Folder 273)
    - Stokowski, Leopold, 1957-1974 (Box 20, Folder 273a)
    - 'T' - 'W' general, 1941-1982, undated (Box 20, Folder 274)
    - Women's Independent Film Exchange, 1977-1984, undated (Box 20, Folder 275)
    - 'Y' general, 1974-1981 (Box 20, Folder 276)
    - Third party correspondence, 1939-1978 (Box 20, Folder 277)
    - First name only, 1958-1980, undated (Box 20, Folder 278)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1975-1980, undated (Box 20, Folder 279)
    - Notes and lists of addresses, 1968-1982, undated (Box 20, Folder 280-283)
      Includes handwritten drafts of outgoing letters
    - Labels and letterhead, undated (Box 20, Folder 284-285)
    - Empty envelopes, 1967-1985 (Box 20, Folder 286)
  - Writings, talks, appearances and screenings
    - Appearances and screenings, 1963-1980s (Box 21, Folder 287-292)
      Includes ephemera, announcements and notes
    - Speeches and lectures, 1932-1970s (Box 21, Folder 293-298)
    - Writings of Mary Ellen Bute, 1932-1967, undated (Box 21, Folder 299-301)
    - Writings of Others (B-N), 1957-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 302-316)
    - Writings of Others (N continued - W), 1957-1981, undated (Box 22, Folder 317-326)
  - Other papers
    - Filmography, undated (Box 22, Folder 327)
    - Resume and biography, undated (Box 22, Folder 328-329)
    - Legal Papers, 1952-1973, undated (Box 22, Folder 330-339)
      Includes release forms and contracts
    - Financial Papers, 1964-1982, undated (Box 23, Folder 340-343)
    - General notes and "to-do" lists, undated (Box 23, Folder 344-345)
    - American Film Institute logo, undated (Box 23, Folder 346)
    - Photographs, 1969, undated (Box 23, Folder 347-350)
      Includes photographs from unidentified film productions
- Personal Papers, 1907-1984; Series III; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  Series III is arranged by format.
  Series III includes family correspondence of Mary Ellen Bute and Ted Nemeth, photographs and legal and financial records. The series also includes ephemera from Bute's memorial service.
  - Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically. Letters of condolence for Mary Ellen Bute's death and postcards, greeting cards and invitations are filed together after the alphabetic sequence.
    - 'B' general, 1977-1980 (Box 24, Folder 351)
    - Bute, Mary Ellen to Ted Nemeth, 1964, undated (Box 24, Folder 352)
    - 'C' - 'M' general, 1907-1982, undated (Box 24, Folder 353)
    - Nemeth, James, 1967-1968, undated (Box 24, Folder 354)
    - Nemeth, Theodore, Jr., 1952-1984, undated (Box 24, Folder 355-356)
    - Nemeth, Theodore, III, undated (Box 24, Folder 357)
    - 'S' - 'W' general, 1977, undated (Box 24, Folder 358)
    - Letters of condolence for Mary Ellen Bute's death, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 359)
    - Postcards, greeting cards and invitations, 1959-1982, undated (Box 24, Folder 360-362)
    - First name only, 1953-1981 (Box 24, Folder 363)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1977-1981 (Box 24, Folder 364)
  - Notes, including calendars and address books, 1980, undated (Box 24, Folder 365)
  - Notes, including calendars and address books, 1980, undated (Box 25, Folder 366-368)
  - Copies of poems by various authors, undated (Box 25, Folder 369)
  - Financial papers, 1952-1981 (Box 25, Folder 370-374)
  - Medical papers, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 375)
  - Legal papers, 1924, undated (Box 25, Folder 376-380)
  - Family photographs, 1920s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 381-387)
  - Painting, unsigned on paper, undated (Box 25, Folder 388)
  - Mary Ellen Bute memorial service, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 389-391)
  - Audio casssettes, undated (Box 26, Folder 392-393)
    The two cassettes are labeled "A Parkside Evangeline Party" and "Pajama Game"
- Ted Nemeth Studios Papers, 1939-1985; Series IV; 2.09; (5 boxes)
  The Series consists of three subseries: Film and audio production material; Correspondence; Business papers.
  The series documents the work of the Ted Nemeth Studios. This studio was engaged primarily in commercial contract work but Ted Nemeth also collaborated closely with Mary Ellen Bute on her films.
  Production material include notes and background research material, photographs and correspondence.
  - Film and audio production material
    The subseries is arranged alphabetically by title or topic of work. Material from unidentified productions is filed at the end up the subseries under the heading Other film and audio productions.
    - "Boxes", undated (Box 27, Folder 394)
    - "Communicating in Symbols", undated (Box 27, Folder 395)
    - "Holy Father's World-wide Missions", 1962 (Box 27, Folder 396)
    - "Ice Follies", undated (Box 27, Folder 397)
    - James Joyce Society meetings, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 398)
    - "Man to Man in Photography," a speech by Edward Steichen, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 399-402)
      Includes an audio recording of the speech
    - "Mobilcolor", 1981-1982, undated (Box 27, Folder 403-408)
    - "Nightwatch", 1954-1956, undated (Box 27, Folder 409-411)
    - "Rama", 1968 (Box 27, Folder 412)
    - Royal Greek Legation, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 413)
    - "Schlitz 40-Horse Hitch", 1972 (Box 27, Folder 414-417)
    - "Take a Giant Step", 1971 (Box 27, Folder 418)
    - "The War Between Men and Women", 1971 (Box 27, Folder 419)
    - Other film and audio productions, undated (Box 28, Folder 420-430)
  - Correspondence
    - 'A' -'B' general, 1957-1983 (Box 29, Folder 431)
    - Basquin, Kit, 1984-1985, undated (Box 29, Folder 432)
    - 'C' -'D' general, 1957, 1971, undated (Box 29, Folder 433)
    - Dockum, Greta, 1982-1985, undated (Box 29, Folder 434)
    - Dockum, Gretchen, 1980-1982, undated (Box 29, Folder 435)
    - Dockum Research Laboratory, 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 436)
    - 'G' - 'S' general, 1948-1982, undated (Box 29, Folder 437)
    - Starr, Cecile, 1981-1985, undated (Box 29, Folder 438)
    - 'U' - 'Y' general, Unidentified correspondent, 1944-1983 (Box 29, Folder 439)
    - List of names and addresses, undated (Box 29, Folder 440)
    - Letterhead, undated (Box 29, Folder 441)
  - Business papers
    - Contracts and licenses, 1942-1985, undated (Box 29, Folder 442-445)
    - Financial records, 1936-1985, undated (Box 29, Folder 446-448)
    - Promotional material, undated (Box 29, Folder 449-452)
  - Notebooks and address books, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 453-468)
  - Photographs, 1950s-1981, undated (Box 31, Folder 469-475)
  - Printed material, 1939-1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 476-483)
- Printed Material, 1936-1985; Series V; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Series V is organized under two headings: Clippings and Ephemera. Printed material that relates directly to a particular film production is filed in Series I under the title of the film.
  The printed material in Series V relates to Mary Ellen Bute and her work and to topics related to film, theater and culture, especially of New York City in the 1970s. Clippings include newspaper and journal articles. Ephemera includes theater programs, conference brochures and leaflets.
  - Clippings
    - Mary Ellen Bute, 1936-1983 (Box 32, Folder 484-496)
    - James Bute, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 497)
    - Margo Lyon, 1971-1980 (Box 32, Folder 498)
    - Other topics, 1953-1985, undated (Box 32, Folder 499-506)
  - Ephemera, 1958-1982, undated (Box 32, Folder 507-510)
  - Ephemera, 1958-1982, undated (Box 33, Folder 511-516)
- June 2008 Addition, circa 1908-1983; 0.42; (1 box)
  The June 2008 Addition is arranged as received by the Beinecke Library.
  The June 2008 addition consists of papers that Cecile Starr removed from the Mary Ellen Bute Papers during the time they were stored at the Yale Film Study Center (prior to their transfer to the Beinecke Library). In 2008 they were returned to the Film Study Center and subsequently transferred to the Beinecke Library.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transfer from the Film Study Center, 2008.
  - Bute booklets, undated (Box 36, Folder 534)
  - University around the world. Postcards, circa 1926 (Box 36, Folder 535)
  - University around the world. Ephemera, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 536)